Finding Aid for the Frank Lawrence Owsley Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Research Materials
  - King Cotton Diplomacy
    - Notecards
      - List—Names of Foreign Ministers, Librarians, Consuls, etc. (Box 30, Folder 10)
Benjamin, Harold, 1947: re: confirmation of appointment for summer session, University of Maryland.
Bennett, J. Jefferson, 1956; re: congratulations on Fulbright.
Benson, Carl, 1955; re: request to participate in panel.
Bernier, Charles, 1952; re: obituary of brother, Dr. W.M. Owsley.
Berthoff, Howland T., 1952: re: Southern opposition to immigration.
Bethea, Barron, 1955; re: Jefferson's agrarian society.
Bettersworth, John K. (2), 1950; re: address at Mississippi State.
Bills, Mrs. Hay, 1953; re: contest in Bedford County, Tenn.
*Binkley, William C. (13), 1931-54; re: graduate work at Vanderbilt (1930's); reorganized program; material in census (1937); Chancellor Kirkland's resignation (1937) and Carmichael as successor; Tennessee Historical Society (1937); athletic situation at Vanderbilt (1951); life in Huntsville, 1880-95; subject for thesis; Joe Lehmann; move to Tulane; research projects (1954).
Bird, Gerald D. (2), 1935; re: desire for scholarship funds.
Bird, Susan (McGehee) (2), 1931, 1935; re: McGehee family.
Black, Hugo L., 1935; re: Bankhead's bill for tenant farmer; tariff; and I'll Take My Stand.
Bolton, Herbert (2), 1926; re: Owsley as possible candidate for position at University of California; article "Defeatism in the Confederacy."
Bolton, Mary (2), 1920; re: summer session at Chicago; trial marriage, etc.
*Bonds, A. B., Jr, 1941; re: use of quotation from "Pillars of Agrarianism."
Bonham, M. L., 1940; re: article on "Economic Basis of Society in Late Ante-Bellum South."
Bonner, James C, 1950; re: speech at Carrolton, Ga.
*Borsodi, Ralph (2), 1937; re: tenant farmers and agrarianism.
Bourne, Henry C. (2), 1936; re: round table on Confederate government.
Bradley, Harold W., 1955; re: invitation to Vanderbilt Party at SHA.
Bragg, James W., 1953; re: teaching position available.
Bramblett, Fred (4), 1953-54; re: requirements for the Master's degree and other ideas.
Branscomb, Harvie (10), 1948-55; re: textbooks, Fulbright recommendation and candidates for chairman of History Department.
Branscomb, L. C., 1920; re: C.G. Daniels.
Breedlove, J.P., 1937; re: inter-library loan of census books.
Brockman, Allan (2), 1953; re: study of Francis Ticknor, physician and poet.
Brogdon, Harriette B. (14), 1939-56; re: former teacher and friend of Frank Owsley.
Bromley, Elizabeth Walker (2), 1952, 1958; re: diary and letters of Walker family, Huntsville, Ala.
*Brooks, Cleanth (7), 1934-39, re: writings and literary discussions, and proposed essays for Southern Review.
Brooks, R. P., 1938; re: writings for volume on contemporary Georgia.
*Brown, C. K.. 1937; re: regionalism and The American Review.
Brown, J. V., 1928; re: notes due Auburn.
Brownback, Peter (2), 1951,55; re: curriculum at University of Alabama and invitation to visit in Washington.
Bryan, T. Conn (2), 1954; re: summer teaching and paper at SHA.
Buck, Paul H., 1945; re: "The Pattern of Migration and Settlement on the Southern Frontier."
Buck, Solon J., 1940; re: article on economic basis of society and agricultural census.
Buford, James L. (3), 1949-56: re: Larry and Margaret's credits and applications.
Burbank, Lyman B., 1952; re: writings and summer teaching position.
Burgess, E.W., 1918; re: course in psychology.
Caldwell, Betty, 1954; re: good wishes.
Caldwell, John T. (2); re: Alabama College, etc.
Canfield, Cass, 1947; re: contract for The Confederacy in The Rise of the American Nation series.
Campbell, Mary R., 1935; re: work for Ph.D.
Carey, L.J. (5), 1953-54; re: collecting manuscripts.
Carmichael, Oliver Cromwell (9); re: writings, Presidency of University of Alabama and difficulties faced.
Carroll, E. Malcolm (2), 1954; re: teaching position at Duke.
Carpenter, William T., 1954; re: Sons of American Revolution.
*Carter, Thomas H. (3); re: article on agrarians in the Shenandoah.
Caskey, W. M. (11), 1933-56, re: writings on Louisiana and his teaching positions.
Cate, Wirt Armistead (3), 1935-36; re: reviews of his books and other writings.
*Cauley, T. J. (2), 1935; re: Resettlement Administration and rural rehabilitation.
Cayton, Horace R., 1933; re: Scottsboro case.
*Chambers, D. L. (2), 1936; re: Long Night by Andrew Lytle.
Chapman, J. Kenton, 1943; re: appreciation of assistance and of personal qualities.
*Chappell, James E. (6), 1935-51; re: writings in American Review; Carmichael's situation at Vanderbilt and other Vanderbilt problems of Board of Trust.
Chase, Henry B., 1952; re: speech to Huntsville Historical Society.
Chenault, Betty Ann, 1953, to A. B. Moore; re: Southern history.
Cheney, Brainard (2), 1946, 1950; re: Plain Folk and the research for it.
Chicago Press, University of (9), 1924-54; various editors and assistants including R. F. Holloway, G. J. Laing (10), Mary Irwin (2), W. R. Jordan, and Jean DeVare; and John T. McNeill.
Chitwood, Oliver Perry (94), 1940-55; re: writing of American history textbook.
Church, William T. (2), 1942; re: desire to continue graduate study.
Clark, A. N. -- see Van Nostrand - Clark.
Clark, Blanche Henry (3), 1935-40; re: work on dissertation. See also: Weaver, Blanche Henry Clark.
Clark, Sam L. (2), 1951; re: representative of Phi Alpha Theta.
Clark, Thomas D. (12), 1945-54; re: Various history projects, Blazer lectures, etc.
Cochran, Perry, 1956; re: Ph.D. work.
Coleman, Charles H. (3), 1934-53; re: historical research and address on Lincoln in Illinois.
Coleman, James S., 1950; re: historical data.
Coles, Harry (15), 1942-55; re: research for doctoral dissertation, Linden, Flanders, Shugg, Futrell, South, Jordan, et al; Ohio State.
Collins, Seward, 1935; re: congratulations on article.
Comer, Donald, 1950; re: article on Clays.
Commager, Henry Steele (3), 1947-48; re: volume on Confederacy in new American Nation Series.
Conover, Frederick L. (4), 1944-55; re: letter of recommendation and friendly letter.
Cooper, John Irwin, 1955, re: Admiral Raphael Semmes.
Cooper, Robert F., 1920; re: personal news of former colleague at Birmingham-Southern College.
Corlew, Robert E. (16), 1953-55, re: doctoral work at University of Alabama and work book for American history textbook.
Cotton, Thomas, 1934; re: recommendation.
Coulter, E. Merton (9), 1933-54, re: historical programs and writings.
*Couch, W.T. (7), 1934-35; re: publication of student's historical writings and agrarianism.
Cox, Carl S., 1920; re: new position in Florida.
Cox, Frederick J. (3), 1952-53; re: Fulbright Fellow in Egypt, experience, etc.
Crabb, A. L., 1949, re: regrets departure of Frank Owsley.
Craig, Daisy D., 1952; re: speech to Moble Society.
Crane, Edward. See D. Van Nostrand -- Crane.
Crane, Verner W., 1940; re: reprint.
*Craven, Avery O. (14) 1953-56; re: historical writings, symposium for Dodd, reprints, etc.
Cresap, Bernarr (5), 1950-54; re: teaching position, historical writings, etc.
Crittenden, C. C. (4), 1935-40; re: articles in North Carolina Historical Quarterly.
Cruickshank, Earl F. (2), 1936-42, re: experiences in U.S. Array.
Curlee, Erline, 1951; re: homecoming at Cain's Chapel.
Curt, Merle (3), 1940-48; re: reprints of articles.
Dale, E. E., 1952, to A. B. Moore; re: lecture tour.
Dale, W.P., 1953; re: former student at Howard College.
Dambrink, John, 1952; re: desire to continue graduate work.
Daniel, C. C. (3), 1919; re: position at Birmingham-Southern College.
Daniels, Francis Clifton, 1954; re: recommendation.
*Daniels, Jonathan, 1936; re: "A Letter to the Yankees."
Davenport, F. Garvin (9), 1940-53; re: historical writings and application for grant.
*Davidson, Donald (11), 1935-52; very fine letters about Agrarians and Fugitives.
Davidson, John (11), 1945-54; re: graduate work at Yale, doctoral dissertation and historical, writings.
Davidson, Philip (6), 1936-49; re: academic affairs, salaries, etc.
Davis, Charles S. (2); re: teaching positions.
Davis, Edwin A. (3), 1953; re: qualifications of students.
Davis, Lambert (15); re: writing for Virginia Quarterly Review.
Dawson, Ed, 195-; re: recommendation.
Denbo, Bruce F. (6), 1949-55; re: reading manuscripts for the Press.
Denman, Clarence P. (2), 1932, 1946; re: series of brief studies on topics of American history.
Denson, N. D. (2), 1952; re: address to U.D.C.
Des Champs, Margaret Burr (13); 1949-55
De Witt, Mrs. John H., 1946; re: election to membership of Tennessee Historical Commission.
Dickerson, O. M. (2), 1955; re: reprint on Revolution.
Diemer, G. W., 1955; re: application of student.
*Dodd, William E. (4), 1931-35, re: King Cotton Diplomacy; articles in American Review; and agrarianism.
Dorman, Lewy (6), 1933-55; re: politics; Barbour County, Alabama; and dissertation.
Dorrance, Ward Allison, 1938; re: appreciation.
Dorris, J. T., 1952; re: publication of his book on Lincoln.
Doster, James F. (9), 1953-54; re: work at Harvard and headship of History Department.
Douglas, Mary S., n.d.; re: book review.
Dowell, Madie, 1919; re: girls basketball team.
Dowell, Spright, 1918; re: teacher's certificate.
Du Bois, W. E. B., 1942; re: resignation from SHA.
Duncan, L. N. (4), 1942-45; re: Dr. Petrie's memoirs.
Duncan, O. D., n.d.; re: writings.
Dunning, William A. (2), 1917; re: graduate study at Columbia University.
D. Van Nostrand Company, 1940-54; Brown, Harold S. (2), 1954; Clark, A. N. (21), 1941-54; Gander, Gustav H., 1952; Gum, William Lee, 1952; Heany, Arthur G. (12) 1949; Van de Velde, L. R., 1940; Victor, O.A., 1952; Crane, Edward M. (25), 1940-50 (especially good regarding various phases of textbook writing); Crane, Edward M., Jr., 1956.
*Dyer, John Percy (26), 1934-50; re: writings, schools, agrarians, etc.
Dykes, R. O., 1919, re: program of commencement.
Eades, William, 1952; re: former student.
Earle, Edward Mead, 1938, re: King Cotton Diplomacy.
Easterby, J. H. (2), 1940; re: meeting of SHA in Charleston.
Edelston, Emily, 1933; re: England.
Edwards, Everett E., 1940; re: reprint on "Economic Basis of Society," etc.
Edwards, J. E., 1956, re: Anglo-American Conference.
Eidson, John O. (2), 1953; re: article on D. R. Hundley.
Ellis, Elmer (2), 1935-36; re: program of MVHA; teaching position.
Elmore, Col. Vincent M., 1951; re: archives position of Mrs. Elmore.
Emerson, O. B., 1953; re: fellowship.
England, J. Merton (2); 1954-55; re: article and Blazer lecture.
*England, Robert (2), 1935; re: proposed conference of Southern Editors; laments trouble with Virginia Quarterly; proposes new literary magazine.
English, Sara John, 1953; re: speech on Lincoln.
Evans, Edward H., 1952; re: teaching positions.
Faircloth, J. M., 1953; re: research project honor.
Faremont, Marquis de Champvans de, 1938; re: membership in Conseil Historique et Heraldique de France.
Farish, Hunter D., 1940; re: reprint of "Economic Basis of Society."
Farraud, Max, 1940; re: reprint of "Economic Basis of Society."
Faulkner, Harold W., 1940; re: reprint of "Economic Basis of Society."
Favrat, Leo M. (2), 1936; re: research grant.
Feidelson, Charles N. (2), 1931, 1934; re: Owsley's book and son's scholarship.
Fields, Emmett B. (2), 1954; re; program for SHA.
Finney, Bob, 1952; re: doctoral exam.
Fishel, Rabbi H.A., 1953; re: Religion in Life week.
Fisher, Le Hoy H., 1954; re; nominations for SHA.
Flanders, Ralph B., 1937, re: program for SHA.
Fleming, Mary Boyd, 1930; re: appreciation for dedication of I'll Take My Stand.
Fleming, Walter Lynwood (4), 1920-27; re: position at Vanderbilt, courses, and grant.
*Fletcher, John Gould (12), 1933-35; re: agrarianism, boycott of Virginia Quarterly, writings, etc.
Ford, Guy Stanton (2), 1947, 1951; re; Linden's review; advisory committee on census.
*Forrester, Donal F. (2), 1933-34; re; comparison of agrarians with Belloc, Chesterton, et al.
Freeman, Douglas Southall (2), 1935; re; review of R. E. Lee.
Friedman, Hugo (4), 1949-53; re; writings and appreciation.
Friedrich, Carl J., 1935; re; historical approach to political science.
Fulbright correspondence -- Young, Francis A. (3), 1956; re; Fulbright assignment and recommendations.
Fuller, Grady (3); 1955; re; research and writing.
Fulton, R. E., 1950; re; Friersons.
Gachel, Dana, n.d.; re; MeGehee family.
Gallalee, John M. (4), 1949-52; re:speech and writings.
Ganaway, Loomis, 1945; re; Army experiences.
Gardner, John W., 1954; re; list of books which would give foreign readers a balanced picture of U. S.
Garner, J. W., n.d.; re; program of AHA.
Gewehr, Wesley M. (3), 1947; re; summer teaching at University of Maryland.
Gewin, Walter P., 1954; re; resignation.
Gilbert, William E. (2), 1954; re; teaching position.
Gill, William H., 1953; re; recommendation.
Glenn, L. C. (2), 1950; re; books.
Going, Allen (6), 1951-52; re: writings, health, salary, promotion, etc.
Govan, Tom, 1954; re: program of SHA.
Gower, Herschel, 1952; re: thesis on Agrarians.
Graham, Jane Kirkland (5), 1932-55; re: Vanderbilt, and her manuscript book.
Graves, John Temple, 1955; re: writings and I'll Take My Stand.
Greaves, Carl P. (2); re: graduate work.
Green, Fletcher M. (8), 1936-50; re: SHA, writings, etc.
Greene, J. N. (2), 1953; re: Alabama Hall of Fame.
Greenfield, Kent Roberts (4), 1935; re; program of AHA.
Gregory, Lillian, 1935, re: book.
Griffith, Lucile (2), 1953; re: I'll Take My Stand.
Griffin, Richard W., 1952; re: graduate work.
Grimmett, Floy, 1952; re: speech to U.D.C.
Guyton, Walter, 1954; re; graduate work.
Hails, Frances M., 1942; re: reprints.
Hall, Fitzgerald (7), 1943-44; re: courses in American history; nonslaveholder in South.
Hall, Martin (2), 1956; re: teaching position and appreciation.
Hamilton, Lillian C., 1954; re: speech in Mobile.
Hammill, Grace, n.d.; re: whereabouts.
Harcourt, Alfred (2), 1926; re: novel on Civil War.
Hart, Laura Louise, 1953; re: student's record.
Hartje, Bob, 1955; re: dissertation and teaching positions.
Harper, Roland M. (9), 1933-42; re: American Review; South misrepresented; writings on land tenure, etc.
Harrell, Costen J., 1944; re: Sam Jones.
Harris, T. H., 1934; re: recommendation.
Hauser, Ernst O. (2), 1936; re: Scottsboro article.
Hawthorne, Frank H., 1949; re: return to Alabama.
Hayes, Joseph P., 1935; re: article in American Review.
Haynes, Jim, 1935; re: combatting communism.
Head, Holman (3); 1953; re: teaching position.
Hendrix, Noble, 1952; re: quotation from Charles A. Beard.
Henry, Robert, 1941; re: SHA presidential address.
Higginbotham, S. W., 1953; re: articles on Mississippi history.
Hill, Louise Biles (4), 1933-51; re: academic problems.
Hill, Walter B., 1936; re: physical examination.
Hingers, Edward, 1953; re: graduate work.
Hobeika, John E. (2), 1936; re: Southern history.
Hoffman, Don, 1954; re: greetings of Phi Alpha Theta.
Hoffman, Philip G. (10), 1952-53; re: extension courses.
Hofstadter, Richard, 1954; re: article on slavery.
Hohenberg, Adolphe (2), 1919; re: recommendation.
Hoke, K. J., 1936; re: summer teaching position.
Holliday, R. H., 1926; re: State Rights in Confederacy.
Holt, Henry and Company -- John E. Neill and Alden H. Clark; re: book on Old South.
Holt, W. Stull (2), 1933, 1940; re: dissertation-subject originality; article on Economic Basis.
Holton, Holland (3); 1937-40, re: summer teaching.
Hoole, W. Stanley (5); 1949-54; re: speech at Alabama Historical Association; teaching-at Columbia, etc.
Horton, George E., 1933; re: writings on the South.
House, R. B. (2), 1926, 1939, re: copyright of material; summer session at Chapel Hill.
Howard, G. H., 1951; re: records of Coosa County.
Howell, Isabel (55), 1949-56, to Harriet Owsley; re: all sorts of interesting people and ideas.
Howell, Morton (11), 1949-55, re: insurance, etc.
Hubert, Ruth B., 1953, re: evaluating manuscript.
Huff, A. Le Roy (4), 1934-35; re: teaching etc.
Ingram, Irvine G. (2), 1949, re: speech at Carrolton, Ga.
Inzer, Peggy Jean (2), 1954-55; re: Speech at Judson College.
Izard, Thomas C., 1934; re: Columbia Summer School.
Jackson, Kenneth, 1950; re: graduate work and teaching Civil War and Reconstruction.
James, Kathrina, 1950; re: University Research Committee.
Jemison, Robert, 1949; re: address to Alabama Historical Association.
Jenkins, William T., 1951; re: graduate fellowship.
Jernegan, M. W. (3), 1934, 1935; re: maps and speech.
Johnson, C. E., 1921; re: cartoons in The Montgomery Journal.
Johnson, Samuel A., 1936: re: dissertation.
Johnston, G. Burke (3), 1951-52; re: teaching position.
Jones, Millard Van, 1953; re: teaching position.
Jordan, Holman D., 1952; re: desire to study at Alabama.
Jordon, Weymouth Tyree (23), 1935-56; re: research and writings, teaching positions, etc.
Karl, Barry D., 1954; re: ms. for U. of C. Press.
Karlin, J. Alexander, 1941; re: Presidential address.
Kendrick, B. B., 1937; re: Tates', teaching position.
Kennedy, Joseph M., 1938; re: Harmsworth professorship.
Kethley, W. M. (2), 1953; re: teaching position.
Kiger, Joseph C. (13), 1951-55; re: teaching positions and research work.
Kilby, Thomas, 1919; re: recommendation.
Kimura, Kikuya (4), 1951-55; re: reprints and bibliography.
Kinard, James C., 1945; re: recommendation.
Kirkland, James H. (6), 1927-56; re: salary and leaves; also appreciation for friendship.
Knapp, Charles M. (2), 1934-35; re: organizing Southern Historical Association.
Knopf, Alfred A. (5), 1938-44; re: contract for proposed book and advanced royalties.
Krauskopf, Frances, 1955; re: book review.
Krock, Arthur (2), 1939; re: Harrasworth professorship.
Krout, John A., 1940; re: reprint of article on "Economic Basis."
Krueger, E. J., 1940; re: reprint of article on "Economic Basis."
*Kuhlman, A. F. (3), 1942-43; re: proposal to establish Fugitive-Agrarian collections.
Landruth, Harold F., 1954; re: graduate school.
Lane, Kate, 1948; re: appreciation for tribute to Dr. Petrie.
Lamer, E. A., 1934; re: George Washington as Virginia gentleman.
Larsen, Laurence M. (5); 1936-37; re: Summer school at University of Illinois.
Lasky, Melvin J., 1941; re: article on "Economic Basis."
Latimer, John (5); 1947-50; re: teaching position.
Lazenby, Candler, 1934; re: teaching German.
Le Breton, Maurice (3), 1951-52; re: French Archives.
Le Due, Thomas (2), 1950; re: methodology in studying land tenure.
Lefler, Hugh T., 1939; re: SHA.
Lehmann, Joseph H. (4), 1953; re: teaching position.
Lewis, Louise Garland, 1950; re: Croxton's Raid on University of Alabama.
Lipsey, Plautus Iberius, 1952; re: textbook on Civil War, etc.
Little, Brown, & Company (3); Herbert F. Jenkins, 1936; re: request for manuscripts on South.
Lloyd, Arthur Young (l4), 1934-49; re: dissertation, teaching, public welfare, and Legislative Research Commission.
Locket, Mary, n.d.; re: thanking for dinner party.
Lord, Clifford (8), 1952-53; re: American Association for State and Local History.
Louisiana Press, 1953; re: death of Wilkerson; evaluation of manuscripts; volumes on Civil War.
Lowes, Marvin McCord (9), 1934-35; re: articles and book reviews for American Review.
Lusky, Lehman M., 1941; re: seeking a job.
Lyle, Olive, 1954; re: speech to Mobile Historical Society.
Lynch, William O., 1950; re: review of Plain Folk.
*Lytle, Andrew (28), 1934-56; re: The Long Night, agrarianism, and other writings.
McCann, Thomas R. (2), 1954; re: graduate work.
McGehee, Edward (11), 1943-51; re: experiences in the armed services; proposed writings and graduate study.
McGill, John T., 1937, re: Phi Beta Kappa membership.
McGrew, Mason, 1950; re: position and research.
McIntosh, John W. (2), 1934; re: graduate work.
McLaughlin, A. C., 1921; re: work at University of Chicago.
McLean, Ross H. (3); 1939-40; re: SHA programs in European history.
McLemore, R.A. (2), 1945-49; re: writings and position at University of Alabama.
McLure, John R., 1952; re: student examination.
McPherson, Joseph, Sr., 1953; re: accident of Joseph, Jr.
McPherson, Joseph, Jr. (2), 1954; re: resignation as graduate assistant.
Manning, John (9), 1934-47; re: research, speaking engagements, teaching positions University of Kentucky, National Institute of Public Affairs, and political job in Kentucky.
Marchant, Alexander, 1950; re: Rolls Royce.
Markey, Morris, 1926, re: using historical works for fiction.
Martin, John M., 1952; re: graduate work.
Martin, Roscoe C. (2), 1949; re: acceptance of position at Alabama.
Martin, Thomas P. (2), 1934; re: establishment of a National Archives and the position of Archivist.
Meacham, Boyd, 1935; re: purchase of farm.
Meade, Robert D. (3), 1940-44; re: SHA program, and his Benjamin book.
Meadows, Austin, 1955; re: adoption of Alabama history textbooks.
Measomer, M. B., 1935; re: graduate work.
Merritt, Edgar C., 1953; re; McGehee family.
Miles, T. J., 1948; re: school associations.
Miller, Francis P. (6); re; agrarianism, articles in American Review and Southern Review.
Milton, George Fort, 1935; re: Lincoln's attitude on Crittenden compromise.
Mims, Edwin (2), 1950; re: Plain Folk.
Mississippi Valley Historical Association (2), 1937-40; re: annual meeting and payment of dues.
Moe, Henry Allen (12), 1927-55; re: Guggenheim Fellowships and friendly messages.
Moffatt, Charles H. (5), 1943-52; re: graduate work.
Moffitt, James W. (3); 1936-39; re: SHA and Southern historical scholarship.
Mooney, Chase (6), 1950-54; re: research and writings.
*Moore, Albert Burton (93), 1917-55; re: schools, writings, football, politics, University of Alabama, teaching positions, graduate program, etc.
Moore, Charles, 1926; re: article on defeatism.
Moore, Glover (10), 1940-50; re: array services, Hitler, Roosevelt, Civil War writings, politics, dissertation publication, etc.
Moore, J. M., 1917; re: old friendship.
Morgan, Helen, 1952; re: history of Clarke County.
Morgan, Walter M. (2), 1956; re: politics, and school problems.
Morris, Richard B. (3), 1953-54; re: summer teaching at Columbia and criticism of article dealing with South.
Morton, Richard L. (3), 1936-46; re: teaching position at William and Mary; article on pattern of migration with request for article for Quarterly.
Morison, S. E., 1940; re: reprint.
Mudroch, Vratislav, 1926; re: School of Music.
Mullins, Edna Earle (2), 1953; re: graduate work at Yale.
Murphy, Rev. DuBose, 1955; re: Biblical references.
Murphy, T. F., 1938; re: purchase of census microfilms.
Neese, Joseph Maynard (5), 1936-39; re: work in North Carolina.
Nettels, Curtis (3), 1934-42; re: thesis on Emigrant Aid Society, policies of 1850's, and comments on reprint on Economic Structure of Rural Tennessee.
Nevins, Allan (9), 1939-54; re: University of Jerusalem, recommendation of his student; invitation to visit.
Nevins, Mrs. Allan, 1954; re: directions for trip to Connecticut.
Newman, J. H., 1953; re: operation Bootstrap.
Newsome, A. R. (2), 1934-38; re: Archives and teaching position.
Newton, Wesley P., Jr., 1953; re: graduate work.
Nichols, Roy F., 1943; re: reprint of article on Economic Basis.
*Nixon, H. C. (24, 1926-56; re; experiences in Europe; politics and FDR; farm tenancy; Pillars of Agrarianism; refusal to write for Who Owns America; ideas on textbook.
*Odum, Howard (2), 1936, 1940; re; "poor whites" and article on Economic Basis of Society.
Oliver, Dr. Oren A. (2), 1947-50; re: orthodontics.
Oliver, Revils Pendleton (2), 1935; re: Three American Crusades.
Omicron Delta Kappa Society (2), 1948; re: appointment as faculty adviser.
Owen, Marie Bankhead (4), 1941-53; re: article on "Fundamental Cause of the Civil War" and other writings.
Owen, Thomas M., Jr. (2), 1935; re: biography of General Joseph Wheeler.
Ownbey, Richard L., 1950; re: Plain Folk.
Palmer, Gordon D., 1953; re: A. B. Moore.
Palmer, John (2), 1946, 1947; re: essay book review.
Park, No-Yong (10), 1951-52; re: lectures and teaching.
Parks, Edd, 1938; re: recommendation.
Patrick, Joseph B., 1954; re: graduate work.
Patton, James W. (6), 1939-42; re: SHA.
Peel, Roy V., 1953; re: Census program.
Pentecost, Percy M. (2), 1949-50; re: teaching.